

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

With a career spanning almost ten years in the IT industry, I have developed a wealth of experience across a variety of sectors including development, team leadership, project and product management. My passion lies in creating an environment where teams can perform their best work, and I take great pleasure in helping clients identify and implement the right solutions for their products. I am dedicated to adding value to any organization I work with, and I am eager to grow alongside the company. My extensive experience across different sectors and industries has provided me with a diverse set of skills, including strong leadership and the ability to communicate effectively with diverse stakeholders, which will be instrumental in achieving success for both the company and the clients.

SKILLS

Organizational skills:

Team Leadership

Engineering Management

Project Management

Product Management

- Bussiness Development
- Branding and Marketing

Front-End skills:

- JavaScript, Typescript
- Angular, ngrx, rxjs, Ionic
- Karma, Jasmine
- HTML, SCSS
- · Angular Material, Carbon, PrimeNG
- React

Tools:

- · Git: Github, Azure, Bitbucket
- Project management: Atlassian, Azure
- Mobile development: Android Studio, XCode

EXPERIENCE

Front-End Team Manager | Consultant, Valcon, Sep 2022 - Current, Novi Sad

- Provided leadership, guidance, and support to project team, and clients.
- · Leveraged project management, communication, leadership, and technical skills to successfully deliver complex projects that met client expectations.
- Aligning department goals and objectives with the overall vision and strategy of the organization and project.
- Organizing and monitoring projects tasks to ensure they are delivered on time.
- Acting as a liaison between the Front-End department, CTO, Product Managers, and other internal teams to facilitate efficient communication and collaboration.
- Providing technical expertise as a Front-End Architect, designing and implementing scalable and maintainable solutions.
- · Act as a Front-End consultant, provide guidance and expertise to clients to ensure that the deliverables meet the highest standards of quality and usability.

Founder, Programarko, November 2021 - Current, Online Bussiness

- Created Programarko, an online programming school for children.
- Developed and executed project plans to create and launch the platform, managing budgets and timelines.
- Researched the market and developed pricing strategies for paid courses.
- Conducted market research to identify potential customers and developed and executed email and social marketing campaigns.
- Identified potential partners, including schools and companies, to promote Programarko.
- Implemented a free "Intro" level to increase accessibility for children.
- Improved accessibility to informal education, allowing children from smaller communities to learn to program.
- Created short, engaging video content for children to learn to program and created progress-tracking features.
- Provided email support for children during the course and included links to the solutions to the animations or games created

Partner | Lead Front-End Engineer | Project Manager | Product Owner, Rockdata, Mar 2020 - Jun 2022, Novi Sad / Rotterdam

- As a partner, I was helping stakeholders to build a team in Serbia and to establish a successful company.
- I have successfully managed and led teams through the full lifecycle of projects, from planning and development to delivery.
- Experience as a product owner gave me a deep understanding of product management and how to align the product vision with the client strategy.
- Through my expertise in agile methodologies and leadership, I have been able to provide guidance to stakeholders and managers to effectively run and manage Scrum teams.
- Managed a team of junior developers, providing technical training, coaching, and guidance to ensure their professional growth and development.
- Conducted regular performance reviews and provided feedback to team members to help them improve their skills and grow their careers.
- · Developed and implemented processes and procedures to ensure that the team was working efficiently and effectively.
- Conducted technical interviews and evaluated candidates for front-end positions, ensuring that the team had the skills and expertise needed to deliver high-quality software.
- Designing and implementing scalable and maintainable front-end architecture.
- Developed and enforced coding standards and best practices to ensure that the codebase was maintainable and scalable.

Front-End Developer, CCBill / PhoenixNAP, Sep 2018 - Feb 2020, Novi Sad

- As a Front-End Developer at PhoenixNAP, I actively participated in the development and maintenance of the company's bare metal billing application.
- As a member of a four-person JavaScript team, I supported the backend development team through code reviews and guidance, working towards their growth as full-stack developers.
- I was also responsible for implementing new features, resolving bugs and troubleshooting technical issues on the application. Furthermore, I was given the opportunity to conduct technical interviews for potential new team members to assess their technical skills.

Front-End Developer, Monochrome Ltd, Aug 2017 - Aug 2018, Novi Sad

- I was building client-side applications, including being a team lead for a startup project in the domain of online hotel bookings.
- Additionally, I have acquired a solid understanding of ServiceNow platform, having developed and delivered management service portals for major corporations and banks.
- I am also adept at supporting the development efforts of other team members, having provided guidance and support to developers working on projects such as a Shipping app and a Recipe app.

Front-End Developer | Ul designer, NovaLite, Jan 2016 - Aug 2017, Novi Sad

As Front-End Developer and UI Designer, I have been responsible for for the development of client-side applications including:

- Web Design
- Technical analysis
- Task estimation
- Bug fixes

I also played an active role in the hiring interns process, conducting testing and technical interviews to evaluate potential candidates Additionally, I have been involved in mentoring and coaching interns, helping them to develop their technical skills and advance in their careers.

Co-founder | Front-End developer | Ul designerCo, Awerest, Feb 2014 - Dec 2015, Novi Sad

As a co-founder, I was responsible for:

- Developing HTML themes for the Envato Market, utilizing a multipurpose theme solution that allowed for flexibility and customization to create multiple unique websites.
- Creating custom web pages for clients, to meet their specific needs and requirements.

Mobile Level Designer, Eipix Entertainment, Jun 2014 - May 2015, Novi Sad

As a member of a cross-functional team in the gaming industry, I gained valuable experience in:

- Adapting games for mobile and tablet devices, which required utilizing my expertise in design principles, mobile design, game design, and user experience (UX) to create seamless and intuitive user interfaces and interactions.
- Building my skillset and understanding of game development, through hands-on experience in all aspects of game development and working with a diverse team of developers, designers, and artists and testers.

Stage Manager, Festival of Street Art, 2012 - 2015, Novi Sad

As a stage manager, my responsibilities included:

- · Coordinating and preparing the stage with all necessary technical equipment and infrastructure, in order to ensure a smooth and seamless
- Collaborating with supervisors to organize and manage the line-up and schedule of events and performances.
- Leading and managing rehearsals for performers, bands and technicians, ensuring that all parties are well-prepared for a successful performance.

EDUCATION

Investment Management, Faculty of Technical Sciences, Mar 2013, Novi Sad

As a student, I was an active member of the ESTIEM organization, where I participated in debates, case studies, and organizing student meetups.